

Personal information

Nationality Egyptian

Residence Saudi Arabia

Birthdate 30/03/1981

Marital StatusMarried

Languages Arabic (Native) - English (Very Good)

Contact

- Riyadh
- 00966 54 111 9764

Competences

- Form a long-term Strategies
- ✓ Planning & Organizing
- Techno-commercial business understanding
- Budgeting & Forecasting
- Leadership / Team Management
- Creative Problem solving
- Situation and Problem Analysis
- ✓ Profit / Revenue Growth
- Negotiation
- Presentation

OMAR MOHAMED

SENIOR MANAGER / LEADER / DIRECTOR

Career Objectives

Innovative leader with a thorough high level of technical knowledge, and techno-commercial strategic experience with proven success driving sustainable profitable growth within organizations, increasing sales, and building long-term partnerships with customers/partners through putting and implementing the right strategies, and creating a healthy and productive work environment, provoking team to perform at their best.

Experience

General Manager - KSA

fischer Fixings Middle East | 2021 - Present

- Form the company strategy and assign the long and short term targets.
- Organize the team and allocate the tasks to the team members / departments.
- Put the KPI and evaluate the performance.
- Development plans for the departments and the team.
- Mentorship, coaching and developing the team.
- Promote an exciting and positive work environment that is respectful and challenging.
- Motivating and Lead the team effectively to reach the assigned goals.

Country Manager - KSA

fischer Fixing Middle East | 2017 - 2021

- Field ride to support/coach the sales team members to perform at their best.
- Build a relationship with the decision-makers and key customers.
- Conducting sales meetings with the team to follow up on the work progress, collect and solve any problems.
- Prepare and approve the material projections.
- Monitor the team performance and discipline and propose a correction plan if required.
- Prepare and implement a development plan for each team member

Technical Manager - KSA

fischer Fixings Middle East | 2013 - 2017

- Lead/coach the technical team to prepare the required technical offers effectively.
- Review and approve any design and technical proposals.
- Keep track for the projects applications and remind the sales team of any missing application.
- Prepare the main technical strategy and analyses the products needed for the market.
- Prepare and implement a development plan for each one of the technical team members.

Technical engineer - KSA

fischer Fixings Middle East | 2010 - 2013

- Prepare the required technical proposal for the Varus applications as per the customer need.
- Building a relationship with the key technical persons in the projects & customers.
- Conducting seminars with the customers to present fischer solutions.
- Support the sales colleague to identify and meet the customer needs and won the deals.
- Prepare a weekly plan, send a daily SDR, and Update the applications in CRM.
- Participating in marketing activities.

Design & Site Engineer - Kinda

Kinda | 2007 - 2010

- Site surveying.
- Design of all construction elements: (Different Types of Foundations, Columns, Beams and Different Types of Slabs).
- Preparing detailed AutoCAD Drawings and Calculation Sheets for the overall building.
- Quantities expense of materials required and cost estimate.
- Supervision & Execution

Teaching Assistant

Higher technological institute | 2003 - 2007

- Structure Analysis
- Steel Structure Design
- Reinforcement Concrete Design

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Civil Engineering

Higher technological institute, City | 1997 - 2002

- General Grade: Very good with honor (76.40%).
- Graduate Project: High rise reinforced concrete building, Excellent.

Courses / Training

- Project Management Professional "PMP"
- IIM Customer base business strategy
- IIM Strategic planning
- Train Of Trainer "TOT"
- Leadership skills
- Professional Selling Skills
- Sales Process 7 steps
- Time Management
- Negotiation Skills

References

Guerol Sevim

Managing Director

- fischer Middle East
- **** +971 50 658 3478
- Guerol.Sevim@fischer.ae

Mostafa Elhosseiny

General Manager - Technical

- fischer Middle East
- **4** +971 50 554 3501
- Mostafa.Elhosseiny@fischer.a e

Jayanta Mukharjee

Business Development Advisor

- fischer Bangladesh, Nepal, and Srilanka
- **\(+91 96 746 91611**
- jayantamukherjee3@gmail.co m

Joachim Mauz

Product Manager

- fischer Germany
- **4** +49 170 330 6457
- Joachim.Mauz@fischer.de

Amit Malhotra

Managing Director

- fischer Qatar
- **L** +974 5060 9555
- Amit.Malhotra@fischer.qa